Disaster Awakening Chapter
Part Two
Powerless
saa, wasuremashou sono mirai ga
Come, let us forget about the future...
Planning
Takeshi Oikawa
Akihiro Kawamura
Akihiro Yuasa
Original Work ・ Original Story/Supervision
Ryukishi07/07th Expansion
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni"
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai"
mata chinurarete yuku nante
...ending up stained in blood again.
Series Composition
Toshifumi Kawase
Character Design
Overall Animation Supervisor
Kyuuta Sakai
Art Director
Chikako Shibata
Color Design
Shinji Matsumoto
namanurui kaze toguromaitara
If the soft wind coils up...
Camera Director
Masayuki Kawaguchi
Editing
Masahiro Matsumura
Music
Kenji Kawai
Sound Director
Hozumi Gouda
sore ga tabun aizu
...that is probably a sign.
nukedashitete
Break free.
Opening Theme
"Naraku no Hana"
(Flower in Hell)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Eiko Shimamiya
Tomoyuki Nakazawa
Takeshi Ozaki
kanashisugiru unmei kara
From your heart-wrenching fate.
Music Producer
Music Production
Mei Yoshikawa
Frontier Works
anata wa naraku no hana ja nai
You are not a flower in hell.
Producers
Mika Nomura
Hiroyuki Oomori
Takeshi Okamura
sonna basho de sakanaide
Don't blossom in such a place.
Animation Producer
Animation Production
Kouji Iijima
Studio Deen
sakanaide
Don't blossom there.
karametorarete ikanaide
Don't get entangled.
oto mo naku tobikau toki no kakera
Fragments of time flutter about without a sound.
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
Director
Chiaki Kon
Hi
gu
ra
shi
no
Na
ku
Koro
ni
Kai
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai
（沙都子(さとこ)の鼻歌）
（梨花(りか)）う～ん…
Rika!
（沙都子）
梨花　いつまで寝てるんですの？
How long are you going to keep sleeping?
お布団 片づけないと
I won't let you have breakfast until you put away your futon.
いつまで経っても
食べられませんわよ
[Friday, June 10th]
[Saturday, June 11th]
（沙都子）どうかしましたの？
（梨花）うん？
Is something the matter?
It's nothing!
（梨花）何でもないのですよ
I'm looking forward to your breakfast!
沙都子の朝ご飯 楽しみなのです
にぱ～
A festival in June?
（圭一(けいいち)）
６月の祭りって ずいぶん早いよな
That's pretty early.
（魅音(みおん)）あ？
（圭一）ほら 盆踊りって―
Well...
Isn't a Bon festival dance held around August?
だいたい８月ぐらいじゃないか？
Watanagashi is a bit different from your average summer festival.
（詩音(しおん)）
綿流しは いわゆる夏祭りとは
ちょっと違いますからね
（圭一）へえ
（男性）おっ 若いの！
（レナ･圭一）うん？
Young man!
Did you come to help out?
（男性）
手伝いに来てくれたのかい？
（男性）男手は いくらあっても
足りないからな　大歓迎だぞ
We could always use some more men.
You're more than welcome.
えっ　いや 俺は…
No, I...
（魅音）さすが圭ちゃん
自ら進んで村のために奉仕するとは
That's our Kei-chan!
He performs community service of his own volition.
What a man.
男だねえ
（男性）ハッハッハ
Oh?
（大石(おおいし)）おや？
ずいぶん盛り上がってますね
It's quite lively here.
ヘッ　おやおや 嫌われたものです
Well, well.
Seems I'm not welcome here.
Ooishi-san.
大石さん　警備の下見ですか？
Did you come for a preliminary security inspection?
アッハッハ　そんなところです
Something like that.
It's the fifth year, after all.
さすがに５年目ですからねえ
The fifth year?
５年目？
The successive Hinamizawa mystery murder incidents?
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)連続怪死事件…
（大石）おや　ご存じでしたか
Oh?
Did you know?
It's giving us quite the headache.
これには私どもも頭が痛くって
Why do such incidents keep occurring on the day of Watanagashi?
どうして綿流しの日にばかり
事件が起きるのか…
Sorry to keep you all waiting!
（梨花）お待たせしましたのですう
（レナ）あ！　遅いよ ２人とも
You two are late!
み～…　ごめんなさいなのです
I'm sorry!
Is something wrong?
（沙都子）どうかなさいましたの？
それじゃあ 大石さん
Then, Ooishi-san...
Do your best with your work.
お仕事のほう
頑張ってくださいね
そうするとしましょう
I'll do just that.
Did something happen?
何かあったんですの？
ううん　何でもないよ
It's nothing.
We were just talking about how Rika-chama will be dancing here on the day of Watanagashi.
綿流しの日には―
ここで梨花ちゃまが
踊るんですよって話してたんです
Yeah, that's right.
You will be a Shrine Maiden at the festival, right?
梨花ちゃん
お祭りの巫女(みこ)をやるんだってな
I'm looking forward to the Watanagashi festival.
綿流しの日 楽しみにしてるぜ
巫女姿の梨花ちゃん…
Rika-chan in a Shrine Maiden outfit!
ハア～　かぁいいよう
So cute!
I wanna take her home!
お持ち帰りい～
If Rika-chan disappears after the festival...
祭りの後に
梨花ちゃんがいなくなったら―
...that would settle you as the culprit.
お前が犯人で確定だな
ギクッ
（魅音）
じゃあ 屋台の種類と位置を
チェックしに行こうか
Well then, wanna go check up on the stall types and their positioning?
（レナ）はう～
This year, the four Watanagashi evil...
（魅音）
今年の綿流しの四凶(よんきょう)… じゃなくて
Or rather, including Shion and Kei-chan, the six evil rogues!
詩音と圭ちゃんも加えて六凶爆闘(ろっきょうばくとう)か
We're gonna make a blast!
What's wrong, Rika?
どうかしたんですの？　梨花
あ…　何でもないのですよ
It's nothing!
にぱ～
Excuse me!
（沙都子）お願いしまあす
（店主）
おっ 梨花ちゃま　いらっしゃい
Rika-chama!
Welcome!
にぱ～　お買い物に来たのです
We came to buy something.
うんうん　梨花ちゃまは偉いねえ
You're such a good girl, Rika-chama.
（沙都子）あの 合いびきください
Umm...
Ground meat, please.
今日も いい天気だったねえ
The weather was great today, wasn't it?
I'm sure the weather'll be great on the day of Watanagashi as well...
こりゃあ 綿流しの日も
きっと いい天気…
（梨花）
合いびき肉くださいなのです！
Ground meat, please!
あ… ああ あいよ　合いびきだね
Gotcha!
Ground meat it is.
梨花ちゃまのところは
今日は何だい？
What will you have for dinner today, Rika-chama?
Hamburgers.
ハンバーグなのですよ
そう　そりゃあいいね
I see!
That's great!
Then I'll give you a huge bonus!
じゃあ 梨花ちゃまには
うんとおまけしちゃおう
（男性）おうおう 北条(ほうじょう)の
You damn Houjous!
For how much did you sell out the village?
お前ら なんぼで村売ったんじゃ？
You damn traitors!
（男性）この裏切り者が！
You have no right to breathe this village's air!
お前らに
村の空気を吸う資格はねえ！
Stop breathing and die!
今すぐ息止めて死ね！
（男性）死ね！
Die! Die!
（男性）何なら今から お前ら
北条家をダムに沈めちゃるわ！
How about we bury you Houjous below the dam right now!
How much longer will Satoko and her family...
（梨花）沙都子たちは―
...be scorned by the entire village?
いつまで村中から
白い目で見られるのですか？
The dam war went on for several years.
ダム戦争は数年に及んだからね
Erasing their stigma of "traitors"...
裏切り者という烙印(らくいん)を消すには
きっと同じくらい
...will likely take about just as long.
Here you go!
（店主）はい お待ちどう
It's okay, Rika.
大丈夫ですわよ 梨花
Oh my!
（女性）あら 大変
Here you go, Rika-chan.
（女性）はい 梨花ちゃん
Let's go, Satoko!
（梨花）
行きましょうなのです 沙都子
フンッ！　ううっ…
（亀田(かめだ)）フフン
Sis doesn't even stand a chance...
お姉が全然 歯が立たないなんて
悔しいですわね
This is frustrating.
だいたい なんで甲子園の
ピッチャーが出てくるんですの？
Why is there a national-level pitcher participating, anyway?
When he was in elementary school...
（入江(いりえ)）小学校の時―
...he apparently played for the Okinomiya Titans.
彼は興宮(おきのみや)タイタンズに
所属していたそうです
（レナ）だからって 草野球に
甲子園ピッチャーなんて―
Even so...
...isn't it unfair to bring a national-level pitcher to an amateur baseball game, I wonder?
ズルじゃないかな？　かな？
（入江）うちも みんなに
助っ人してもらってますよ
We've hired a lot of help as well.
Mion-san's grand slam home run was amazing.
魅音さんの満塁ホームランは
すごかったなあ
Okinomiya T
Hinamizawa F
That was good enough to make it through the early innings, but...
（詩音）序盤は
それでよかったんですけど…
（沙都子）亀田さんが
登場してからは 出塁はおろか―
Ever since Kameda-san appeared...
...nobody has been able to even graze the ball, let alone reach first base.
バットに かすりもしないなんて…
みんな 元気出してくださいまし！
Cheer up everyone!
そうですよ
お姉　かっ飛ばせえ！
You're right!
Sis!
Smash it out of the park!
フンッ！
（審判）
ストライク！　バッター アウト
Strike!
Batter out!
（魅音）うう～　チクショー！
Goddamnit!
We're no match for him after all.
（入江）やっぱり歯が立ちませんね
That's not true!
そんなことありませんわ！
目には目を
助っ人には助っ人ですわ！
An eye for an eye!
A pinch hitter for a pinch hitter!
I am telling you, it is an absolute crisis!
（沙都子）ですから
絶対的な危機なんですのよ
このままでは 負けてしまいますわ
At this rate, we will lose!
I'm kinda busy here as well.
（圭一）
こっちも立て込んでてさあ…
I want to join in the club activities soon too, but...
俺も早く部活に加わりたいんだけど
Club activities!?
（沙都子）
部活って 何言ってるんですの？
これは実戦ですわよ！
This is a real fight!
（圭一）じ… 実戦!?
A-A real fight!?
Yes...
Mion-san fought hard, but...
魅音さんが
戦ってくださったんですけど
...she was defeated.
返り討ちに…
（圭一）魅音が!?　ケンカか…
Mion was!?
A brawl!?
分かった　大急ぎで行く！
Understood!
I'll be right over!
How long are you going to keep us waiting?
（審判）
いつまで待たせるんですか？
Just a little longer.
（入江）もうちょっとだけ…
No matter what kind of pinch hitter will show up...
（記者）
どんな助っ人が来たって―
...I think it's meaningless if he's up against Kameda-kun.
亀田君相手じゃ
意味ないと思いますけどねえ
That is not true.
（沙都子）そんなことありませんわ
Keiichi Maebara.
前原(まえばら)圭一
To him, Kameda-san might as well be pitching balloons!
彼が来れば 亀田さんの球なんて
風船玉も同じですわよ
（記者）前原圭一？
Keiichi Maebara?
Who's that?
（記者）誰だ？　それ
（記者）知ってるか？
You know him?
That's right!
そうですわ
あんな へなちょこピッチャーの
球なんて―
Once that novice pitcher's balls hit Keiichi-san's bat...
圭一さんの手にかかれば―
楽勝でバックスクリーンを
越してくださいますわよ！
...they'll fly past the center field screen as if they were nothing!
おーっほっほっほ！
Was there such a slugger sleeping here in the countryside?
そんなスラッガーが
こんな田舎に眠ってたのか
本社に連絡だ
Call the agent!
おーっほっほっほ　来ますわよ！
Here he comes!
我が雛見沢の秘密兵器が
Hinamizawa's secret weapon!
（ベルの音）
（沙都子）ほら！
See!
ぬあっ
前原圭一 ただ今 見参！
Keiichi Maebara, reporting for duty!
あ… あれ？
Huh?
Uh...
（沙都子）あのう 圭一さん
１つ聞いても よろしいですの？
Keiichi-san?
Can I ask you one question?
いや…
Err...
Why a golf club?
どうしてゴルフ？
（圭一）や… 野球の試合なら
初めから そう言え！
If...
If it's just a baseball game then say so from the start!
ぐ…　甲子園ピッチャー？
A national-level pitcher!?
Hey!
こらあ！　ビビってんじゃなーい！
Don't be scared!
バット　振んなきゃ
当たるもんも当たんないでしょうが
You can't hit the ball if you don't swing the bat!
Don't be ridiculous!
バカ言ってんじゃねえよ！
How the hell am I supposed to hit this!?
こんなの どうやって
打てっつうんだよ！　へ!?
ストライク！　バッター アウト！
Strike!
Batter out!
敗色濃厚ですね
Seems we're doomed...
It's not over yet.
まだですわ
There's a special rule in amateur baseball.
草野球ならではの特別ルール…
We can use Keiichi-kun as pinch hitter next inning as well.
次の回にも 代打として
圭一さんを出せるんですのよ
Sure, but in this situation...
といっても あの様子じゃねえ…
Don't worry.
大丈夫ですわよ
私(わたくし)に いい手がありますの
I have a good trick up my sleeve.
What?
（亀田）何!?
I'll say it once more.
もう一度だけ言う
Let us win!
俺たちを勝たせろ
When you were asked in a magazine interview...
君は雑誌のインタビューで―
...you said your favorite food is grilled meat...
好物は焼肉で 嫌いなものは
甘いものだと答えたらしいが―
...and that you hate sweets.
That's a lie, isn't it?
それはウソじゃないのかい？
がああっ…
（圭一）例えば君が―
Suppose you were to go to an all-you-can-eat grilled meat restaurant.
焼肉食い放題に行ったとする
What would be on your plate?
君の皿に盛られてるのは何だ？
Roast pork?
ロースか？　カルビか？
Beef ribs?
あわわ…
（圭一）違うよな？
That's wrong, right?
You really like those pretty and cute western confectioneries...
ほんとは女の子が喜びそうな
きれいで愛くるしい―
...that make little girls squeal with delight, don't you?
そんな洋菓子が大好きなんだよな？
Shishibone's grilled meat chain serves
a large variety of dishes. Please visit!
Information from the Sonozaki house
of the three great Hinamizawa houses!
Wrong!
違う！　俺が好きなのは豪快な
骨付きの…
What I like is hearty...
お前が好きなのは
色とりどりのクリームで
What you like is multicolored, creamy, sweet, cutely served desserts!
優しく かわいく盛り付けられた
デザートだ！
That's right!
そう　まるでフリルやリボンで
飾り付けられた―
They remind you of pure, unsullied girls dressed in frills and lace!
無垢(むく)で汚れを知らぬ少女を
連想させるような―
そんな透き通った少女のような
デザートを―
Eating those desserts is like those girls are being defiled by a pimply, nakedly greedy jock like you!
ニキビだらけの 欲望丸出しの
坊主頭が汚すように―
バリバリ ムシャムシャ…
（亀田）うああ　言うなあ！
Chomp chomp, munch munch! Chomp chomp, munch munch!
Don't say it!
そうだ　お前はデザートを食べ
めでているのではない！
That's right!
You don't eat and enjoy desserts!
汚し 蹂躙(じゅうりん)し
しゃぶり尽くしてるだけなのだあ！
You just defile them, violate them and suck them dry!
ぎゃあー！　俺のひそかな楽しみが
知られてしまったあ！
You've found out my secret guilty pleasure!
もう死ぬしか…
（圭一）バカ野郎！
I'm gonna kill myself...
Dumbass!
命を粗末にするな！
Don't throw your life away!
I'm the only one who has these thoughts while eating desserts...
こんなこと考えて
デザートを食べているのは俺だけだ
俺は変態なんだ…
I'm such a pervert...
そうだ　変態だ
That's right.
You're a pervert!
ぎゃああ！　ううう…
What's wrong with a man being a pervert?
男が変態で何が悪い？
All men are perverts!
（圭一）男は すべからく変態だ
But whether you recognize that or not...
それを認めるか否かで
男の器は天と地の差を持つのだ！
...men are different from each other as heaven and earth!
You were honest with yourself!
お前は自分に素直だった
それを自慢していい
That's something to brag about!
誇っていい！
（亀田）あああ…
Something to be proud of!
Dessert Festa
I have all-you-can-eat coupons for Angel Mort here.
ここに エンジェルモートの
食べ放題チケットがある
I was mistaken!
（亀田）俺が間違ってました！
This is the first time I've met someone like you!
あんたみたいな人に
出会ったのは 初めてです
Okay.
よし　じゃあ
手はずどおり頼んだぜ
I count on you to handle it like we agreed.
W-Wait!
ま… 待って！　せめて お名前を…
At least give me your name!
Just call me "K."
ケイ… とでも呼んでもらおうか
ウハ～…
K!!!
ケーイ！
Kei-chan!
（魅音）圭ちゃん
打たなきゃ罰ゲームだよ！
If you don't hit, it's punishment game time!
はうっ！　何かな？　何かな？
What will it be, what will it be?
（詩音）
そりゃあ もう 全裸で場内一周
That's obvious.
One lap around the neighborhood in the nude.
もちろん逆立ちで
On his hands, of course.
What's wrong, Rika?
どうしましたの？　梨花
You were acting like this this morning as well.
今朝もそうでしたし
元気ありませんわね
You seem down.
Are you still worried about what happened yesterday?
もしかして 昨日のこと
気にしてるんですの？
イヤですわ　私は
全然気にしてませんのよ
Don't.
I'm not bothered by it at all.
沙都子…
Satoko...
Come on.
（詩音）ほら
Start cheering, you two.
２人とも 応援 応援！
思いっきり こい！
Bring it on!
K...
ケイ…
Keiichi-san, keep it cool!
（沙都子）圭一さん しっかり！
かっ飛ばしてくださいまし！
Smash it out of the park!
そうよね
You're right...
Do your best!
（沙都子）頑張れえ！
（梨花）頑張るのです 圭一！
Do your best, Keiichi!
Let's at least enjoy it while I can.
（梨花）せめて今くらいは楽しもう
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni
Kai
（沙都子）試合は逆転勝ち
It was a comeback victory!
まんまと 私の策に
はまりましたわね
They totally fell for my plan.
さすが沙都子なのです
That's great of you, Satoko!
Even a national-level pitcher cowers in fear after dealing with me.
（沙都子）甲子園ピッチャーも
私にかかれば あんなもの
He lacks training!
修行が足りませんわ
私に打たれたときの顔といったら…
You should've seen his face when I hit his pitch...
うん？　梨花？
Rika?
梨花!?　何やってるんですの？
Rika!?
What are you doing?
（沙都子）
どこか具合が悪いんですの？
Are you not feeling well?
み～　何でもないのです
失敗 失敗なのです
It's nothing.
I messed up!
Is it my fault after all?
やっぱり 私のせいですの？
み～？　全然 違うのです
You're totally wrong!
心配いらないのです
You don't need to worry about me.
I just wasn't paying attention.
ただ ボーっとしちゃった
だけなのです
（梨花）
結局 何も変わらないまま―
In the end...
...I will simply repeat death without anything changing again.
私は また死を繰り返すだけ
I just can't get used to...
慣れないものね
失意のうちに死んでいくというのは
...dying in hopelessness.
（羽入(はにゅう)）あうあうあう…
そんなこと
言わないでほしいのです 梨花
Please don't say that, Rika.
また あの日がきて
私は殺されてしまう
That day will arrive again...
...and I will be killed.
いつもと同じように
Just like always.
（羽入）梨花…
Rika!
（梨花）じゃあ 何か変わる？
Then will something change?
変わらないわ 何も
Nothing changes.
Nothing at all.
（羽入）そんなことはないのです
サイコロの目は振ってみなければ…
That's not true.
We have to try and roll the dice again...
何度振っても同じよ
No matter how often we roll, the result is the same.
今度こそはと思って裏切られる
Just when I think I can finally get out...
...I am betrayed.
（羽入）あうあうあう…
我慢強く待てば―
If we wait patiently, a happy world will come around one day!
いつか きっといい世界が
巡ってくるのです
（梨花）それは いつ？
And when will that be?
Don't give up, Rika!
（羽入）諦めないで 梨花
One day we will find something that will allow you to break free...
いつか ここから
抜け出させてくれる何かが…
And what would that be!?
（梨花）何かって何!?
（梨花）どうせ私は
また いつもと同じように殺される
I will just end up getting killed like always!
梨花？
Rika?
Who are you talking to?
誰と話してるんですの？
Was there someone here?
今 ここにどなたか…
（梨花）独り言よ
Talking to myself.
“殺される”とか聞こえましたけど
I heard something about someone getting killed...
誰が？
Who will?
私
I will.
綿流しの後 私は殺されてしまう
After Watanagashi...
...I will be killed.
この運命から逃れることはできない
I cannot escape this fate.
（沙都子）梨花
Rika?
Good morning, Satoko!
（梨花）おはようなのです 沙都子
今 ご飯できるのです
Breakfast is ready.
あの 聞いてもよろしくて？
Umm...
Can I ask you something?
昨日の夜 私―
Yesterday night...
...I was talking to you, wasn't I?
梨花とお話しをしましたわよね？
ここで…
Right here...
About what?
何のことですか？
その…　梨花が殺されるとか…
Well...
About you...
...getting killed, or something.
It was a really strange conversation...
変な話なんですけど
（梨花）
ヘヘ　沙都子は夢でも見たのです
You were probably dreaming.
（沙都子）でも…
But...
早く顔を洗っちゃうのです
Hurry and wash you face.
いつまでも寝ぼけてたら
ダメなのですよ
You can't walk around with a sleepy face forever.
Okay...
Okay!
さあ どこからでも
かかってらっしゃいまし！
Come at me from wherever you want!
サバイバル缶蹴り！
Survival kick the can!
最初に死ぬのは どなたかしら？
Who will be the first one to die?
ヘッ　気分はジャングル戦だな
This feels like jungle warfare.
トラップあるかな？　かな？
Are there traps, I wonder?
ねえわけねえだろ
Obviously.
あれ違う？
（圭一）うん？
Are those the traps?
（圭一）落とし穴か
Pitfalls, huh?
…にしちゃあ あからさまだな
But they're in plain sight.
ブラフで 本命は別…
と思わせるのは当たり前
It's obvious she wants to make us think these are a bluff and the real traps are elsewhere.
No, we have to outsmart her...
いや その裏をかいて…
見切った！
これ見よがしのブラフ
I got her!
It's a false bluff!
Those are the safe spots!
あれこそ安全地帯！
行くぞおー！
Let's move in!
フンッ　無謀ですわね
How reckless.
I saw right through your traps!
お前のトラップは見切れ…
（沙都子）おーっほっほっほ
見切ったとは
よく おっしゃったものですわね
I thought you said you saw right through them?
こんなの引っかかるのは
圭一さんぐらいのものですわよ
You're about the only person who'd ever fall for this...
み～　引っかかったのです
（圭一）なんで!?
I fell for it.
Why?
（沙都子）
ちょっと 何やってますの？　梨花
Hey, what are you doing, Rika?
Are you okay, Rika-chan?
梨花ちゃん どうしちゃったの？
圭ちゃん並みのドジっぷりだねえ
Rika-chan, what happened to you?
Only Kei-chan would normally make such a goof!
こらあ！
Hey!
確かに梨花ちゃまらしくないですね
That's true...
This is unlike you, Rika-chama.
み～　失敗しちゃったのですう
I messed up!
（圭一）梨花ちゃんが殺される？
Rika-chan will be killed?
（詩音）
でも それ 夢の話ですよね？
But that was something from your dream, right?
（沙都子）
とは思ったんですけれど…
Or so I thought, but...
でも 梨花ちゃんを殺す人なんて
この雛見沢にいるとは思えないな
But I don't think anyone here in Hinamizawa would ever think of killing Rika-chan.
ちょっと考えづらいね
It's hard to imagine.
そうだよね　梨花ちゃんは―
That's right.
Rika-chan is practically considered the reincarnation of Oyashiro-sama.
オヤシロさまの生まれ変わりって
言われてるくらいだもん
でも…
But still...
（沙都子）梨花
（梨花）み～？
Rika!
You told me yesterday night, didn't you?
昨日の夜 私に
お話してくださいましたよね？
綿流しの後 梨花が…　う…
That after Watanagashi, you would be...
話してないのですよ
（沙都子）え？
I never said anything like that.
昨日は お布団に入った後
ボクは朝まで ぐっすりなのです
After I went to bed last night, I was sound asleep until morning.
ほら　やっぱ寝ぼけてたんだよ
There you have it.
You were dreaming after all.
（魅音）もう 脅かさないでよ
Geez!
Don't scare us like that!
（沙都子）梨花…
Rika...
まだ寝ぼけてるのですか？　沙都子
Are you still half asleep, Satoko?
（羽入）後悔しているのですか？
Are you regretting it?
そうね　少なくとも
沙都子に聞かすべきではなかった
I guess...
It wasn't something I should have let Satoko hear.
（羽入）でも 沙都子も
言ってたじゃないですか
But...
...didn't Satoko also say...
...that you shouldn't keep things to yourself...
独りで抱え込まずに…
沙都子を巻き込みたいの？
You want to get Satoko involved?
If I tell someone, something will happen to that person.
話せば その人に何か起きる
考えたくもない ひどいことが…
Something so horrible I don't even want to imagine it.
沙都子に… いえ
誰にも救いを求めてはいけないのよ
I can't ask Satoko...
No...
I can't ask anyone for help.
（羽入）梨花…
Rika...
（梨花）たとえ死ぬ運命でも―
Even if I am destined to die...
...all I can do is accept that fate on my own.
私は 独りで黙って受け入れるだけ
（沙都子）梨花？
Rika?
Rika!
梨花!?
Rika...
梨花
It was true...
やっぱり…
（梨花）あなたには何もできない
There is nothing you can do.
（梨花）もう間に合わない
It is already too late.
Cast
Keiichi Maebara
Rena Ryuuguu
Mion Sonozaki
Shion Sonozaki
Satoko Houjou
Rika Furude
Hanyuu
Souichiro Hoshi
Mai Nakahara
Satsuki Yukino
Mika Kanai
Yukari Tamura
Yui Horie
anata no nakigara ni tsuchi wo kakeru
I cover your corpse with soil...
Cast
Kuraudo Ooishi
Kyousuke Irie
Kouichi Kameda
Umpire
Villager
Butcher
Chafuurin
Toshihiko Seki
Kazunari Tanaka
Gen Nakano
Satoshi Tsuruoka
Nobuyuki Kobushi
sore ga kinjirareteita toshitemo
...even though that may have been forbidden.
junsui na manazashi no kairaku ni wa
There was a temptation you could not hide...
kakushikirenai yuuwaku ga atta
...in your pure, blissful eyes.
doushite tsumi ga aru no darou
Why does sin exist?
Ending Theme
"Taishou a"
(Target a)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition/
Arrangement
doushite batsu ga aru no darou
Why does punishment exist?
hori no saki wa amari ni mo shiroku
That blindingly white end of the canal...
mugen ni tsuzuku yami wo sasotta
...invited the infinite darkness.
Scenario
Masashi Suzuki
Storyboards
Episode Direction
Michio Fukuda
Makoto Sokuza
nani mo kamo ga azayaka ni miete
I can see everything clearly now.
Animation Supervisors
Animation Supervision Assistance
Kyoko Kotani
Takako Shimizu
Maki Kawano
Chikai Okado
sugu ni kieteshimau
It will soon vanish.
Animation Production
Studio Deen
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
© 2007 Ryukishi07/Hinamizawa Three Great Houses
The penetrating cries of the cicada's...
（梨花）
胸に染みる ひぐらしの鳴き声
...someone's screams echoing through the lush forests...
新緑にこだまする 誰かの悲鳴
...Oyashiro-sama's indiscriminate curse...
相手構わぬオヤシロさまの祟(たた)り
To savor such horror...
そんな恐怖を味わいに
...come to Hinamizawa!
（羽入）
おいでませ 雛見沢なのですう
Enjoy a stay in the Sonozaki family's deluxe torture suite!
ご宿泊は 園崎(そのざき)家自慢の
特製“拷問部屋”
Booking now nets you front row seats for the Nail Removal Dinner Show!
今なら豪華夕食に―
生爪はがしショーが
もれなくセット
Now with extra blood.
[shukketsu daisa-bisu: A distress sale. Literally, "bleeding service."]
（梨花）出血大サービス中
Next time, the Disaster Awakening Chapter, Part Three.
次回　厄醒し編 其の参
「予定調和」
"Pre-established Harmony."
This offer is brought to you by the Hinamizawa Tourism Association!
提供は
雛見沢観光協会なのですよ
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai
Next time
Disaster Awakening Chapter
Part Three
Pre-established Harmony